<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ricard Clau</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/</link><description>Recent content on Ricard Clau</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 17:00:14 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ricardclau.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2016 retrospective and 2017 goals</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2016-12-19-2016-retrospective-and-2017-goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 17:00:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2016-12-19-2016-retrospective-and-2017-goals/</guid><description>Wow, another year went by! And here we are again doing some retrospective.
I know this is a cheap way to avoid visiting a psychologist but somehow, writing these posts helps me create piece of mind. And many people have told me they like reading them so it´s a win-win situation!
I started the year with a new role: Automation Team Lead at Wonga.
Wonga is a financial services organisation with presence in multiple countries, operating in a heavily regulated environment and this involves a lot of challenges in terms of automation.</description></item><item><title>Technical interviews - Are we all out of our minds?</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2016-07-30-technical-interviews-are-we-all-out-of-our-minds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 11:46:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2016-07-30-technical-interviews-are-we-all-out-of-our-minds/</guid><description>Ah&amp;hellip; the summertime! Lots of feet in the sand pictures, people showing off in Facebook, extreme unbearable heat and most importantly&amp;hellip; holidays time for many people!
And of course, everybody thinks about quitting their shitty jobs during holidays so many chances are you will do some interviews between the 15th of August and the 15th of September as it is the perfect time for companies to hire and it is possibly the time of the year when people are more likely to consider a job change.</description></item><item><title>Running Go executables (Consul, Telegraf, ...) as windows services</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2016-03-23-running-go-executables-consul-telegraf-as-windows-services/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:30:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2016-03-23-running-go-executables-consul-telegraf-as-windows-services/</guid><description>There are many companies building applications using C# which still predominantly run on Windows servers.
Windows 2012 Server was definitely a step forward and I can´t wait to see the first headless Windows Nano servers, which is happening in Windows 2016 Server. However, the Windows ecosystem is sometimes a bit of a step behind the Linux world or has taken a completely different approach (Powershell I am looking at you).</description></item><item><title>Stock Options in Startups - A scam or something worth a shot?</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2016-01-09-stock-options-in-startups-a-scam-or-something-worth-a-shot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 13:52:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2016-01-09-stock-options-in-startups-a-scam-or-something-worth-a-shot/</guid><description>After some years working in startups I thought it was about time to write a blog post with some thoughts and experiences related to the stock options you sometimes get in this type of companies.
When I was in Barcelona I often thought about how great it would be if more companies offered stock options. But this thought has changed lately and I would like to explain why.
Most of this is just plain common sense and some of you may say &amp;#8220;hey, this is very clear in the contract, you should know what you are signing&amp;#8221; but the reality is that most of us don´t know much about these things and only experience teaches us.</description></item><item><title>2015 retrospective and 2016 goals</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2015-12-31-2015-retrospective-and-2016-goals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 13:42:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2015-12-31-2015-retrospective-and-2016-goals/</guid><description>Here we are again, another year has passed and it´s time for retrospective!
This year has been a bit weird for me. A year of reinvention, regeneration and most importantly, making peace with myself. Most of it has happened at a personal level but it has also affected my work.
I have spent all year working at Another Place Productions, a small video game studio in London where I have been able to improve my DevOps knowledge a lot as I was in charge of all the backend and infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Deploying PHP applications with Ansistrano</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2015-10-20-deploying-php-applications-with-ansistrano/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 09:04:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2015-10-20-deploying-php-applications-with-ansistrano/</guid><description>For a very long time, Capistrano was, without any doubt, the de-facto tool to deploy your dynamic languages applications. Now there is a better one, Ansible based, called Ansistrano.
Ansistrano was initially created by Carlos Buenosvinos and is a set of 2 Ansible roles: deploy and rollback. It has almost 200 stars on Github and some large companies are already using it.
In this video you can see how to deploy a small Silex application and you can also see how to rollback and add a small hook reloading the opcache in your production servers.</description></item><item><title>Access to the raw Request body in Play Framework</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2015-06-27-access-to-the-raw-request-body-in-play-framework/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 12:45:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2015-06-27-access-to-the-raw-request-body-in-play-framework/</guid><description>Play Framework uses the concept of BodyParsers to read the data being sent in our HTTP requests. You can read more about this subject in the official docs.
As it can be seen, we can specify an explicit BodyParser in our controller actions as explained in this page but unless we have some specific need we will possibly be better delegating the right parser to the framework.
By default, Play uses the BodyParser.</description></item><item><title>2 años en Londres - Experiencias y aventuras</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2015-06-09-2-anos-en-londres-experiencias-y-aventuras/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 08:13:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2015-06-09-2-anos-en-londres-experiencias-y-aventuras/</guid><description>En el momento de escribir esto, hace algo más de 2 años que aterricé en esta fascinante ciudad en busca de un futuro mejor para mí y mi mujer. Han pasado una infinidad de cosas desde entonces y creo que es un buen momento para hacer balance. Y en vez de pagar una sesión de psicólogo, he decidido escribir un poco al respecto.
He pensado escribir este post en castellano ya que aunque la mayoría de los que me leéis entendéis perfectamente mi incorrecto inglés quiero pensar que esto puede servir a gente indecisa cuyo nivel de inglés quizás no sea muy bueno.</description></item><item><title>2014 retrospective and 2015 goals</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2015-01-04-2014-retrospective-and-2015-goals/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 19:12:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2015-01-04-2014-retrospective-and-2015-goals/</guid><description>It&amp;#8217;s been quite a while since I last wrote an entry in this blog. What the hell, I haven&amp;#8217;t written a single blog post in 2014! And this is a shame. A clear resolution for 2015 is to try to write a bit more here.
Anyway, sorry for another (hopefully not) boring retrospective post. But it&amp;#8217;s been a very complex and intense year for me and I really want to write about it.</description></item><item><title>Resumen 2013 y objetivos 2014</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-12-16-resumen-2013-y-objetivos-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 23:47:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-12-16-resumen-2013-y-objetivos-2014/</guid><description>2012 fue un año muy intenso pero 2013 tampoco se ha quedado atrás
La gran decisión Empecé el año todavía en SocialPoint. Probablemente la aplicación más grande de Symfony y uno de los proyectos más importantes de Europa sin ninguna duda. Rodeado de buenos amigos, excelentes ingenieros, pero algo cansado del ritmo frenético de los meses anteriores. Y ya llevaba unos meses dándole vueltas a la posibilidad de marcharme fuera.</description></item><item><title>4 meses en Londres - Experiencias</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-08-26-4-meses-en-londres-experiencias/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 20:50:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-08-26-4-meses-en-londres-experiencias/</guid><description>Este post no va de tecnología, o por lo menos no va a haber código. Sin embargo, voy a intentar resumir algunas experiencias que he tenido en mis primeros 4 meses en Londres. Tal vez con eso consiga animar (o incluso desanimar, y quizás ahorraros algo de sufrimiento) a todos aquellos que os estéis planteando dar el salto.
Todo viene de unos tweets cruzados con los grandes @asiermarques y @pgodel así que ya sabéis a quién culpar!</description></item><item><title>Symfony2 versus Go: Round 1 - Hello world (static pages)</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-07-21-symfony2-versus-go-round-1-hello-world-static-pages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 16:26:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-07-21-symfony2-versus-go-round-1-hello-world-static-pages/</guid><description>In my new job at Hailo we are introducing Go as the main language in the new architecture and because of that I have started playing with it. Besides that, there has been a lot of comments and opinions in both the Symfony2 and the PHP community regarding the TechEmpower framework benchmarks where Symfony2 appears at the bottom of the list for most of the tests.
Needless to say, PHP is and will always be slower than a compiled new-generation language.</description></item><item><title>APC Settings: stat and shm_size</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-05-18-apc-settings-stat-and-shm_size/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 12:52:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-05-18-apc-settings-stat-and-shm_size/</guid><description>Most of you already know that APC is really important to boost PHP performance. It will probably be replaced in the next months / years by Zend Optimizer+ but meanwhile it is important to know how to properly tweak this amazing PHP extension.
If we have a look at http://php.net/manual/en/apc.configuration.php we will see in the first couple of lines that both stat and shm_size are the most important directives but most people seem to not know about them, and this is why I am writing this post.</description></item><item><title>APC vs Zend Optimizer&#43; Benchmarks with Symfony2</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-03-08-apc-vs-zend-optimizer-benchmarks-with-symfony2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 11:26:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-03-08-apc-vs-zend-optimizer-benchmarks-with-symfony2/</guid><description>If you are following some of the biggest names in the PHP scene you may have seen that Zend Optimizer+ is now open-source on Github at https://github.com/zend-dev/ZendOptimizerPlus and it seems that will be included in PHP 5.5 distribution.
This is awesome news as we will finally get a PHP Accelerator bundled with the main language distribution and there should not be (let&amp;#8217;s hope) weird issues like the ones happening in early versions of PHP 5.</description></item><item><title>Testing Symfony2 Commands - Mocking the DI Container with Mockery</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-02-20-testing-symfony2-commands-mocking-the-di-container-with-mockery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 21:23:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-02-20-testing-symfony2-commands-mocking-the-di-container-with-mockery/</guid><description>Some months ago I had the pleasure to contribute to phpcassa library, maintained by Tyler Hobbs, adding support for Composer and Travis, and fixing some issues with PHP5.4 and some E_STRICT warnings.
And, as there is no Symfony2 bundle for Cassandra yet, I have decided to create one myself. The bundle is at early stages but I have already developed some basic Administration commands, mainly to create a Keyspace, a ColumnFamily, etc&amp;hellip; and I have decided to share here how I have unit-tested those commands.</description></item><item><title>Resumen 2012 y Objetivos 2013</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-01-02-resumen-2012-y-objetivos-2013/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 23:21:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2013-01-02-resumen-2012-y-objetivos-2013/</guid><description>Si 2011 fue movido, 2012 ha sido una auténtica locura.
Resumen Laboral Empecé el año en Ulabox, posiblemente el proyecto web del cual me siento más orgulloso, terminando una larga migración del infame Prestashop a un backend 100% Symfony2. Todo parecía ir bien, pero la crisis no perdona ni a los mejores y el proyecto tuvo una época muy dura con fuertes recortes de personal. Fueron momentos complicados ya que como sabréis todos los que habéis estado en una startup, acabas sintiendo que el proyecto es como un pequeño hijito y creedme que fue muy duro tenerlo que dejar.</description></item><item><title>How to log messages to different files with Monolog in Symfony2.0</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2012-08-20-how-to-log-messages-to-different-files-with-monolog-in-symfony2-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 19:34:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2012-08-20-how-to-log-messages-to-different-files-with-monolog-in-symfony2-0/</guid><description>If you are logging lots of activity in your Symfony2.0 application you might have seen that it is not that obvious to split them into different files.
This has been solved in Symfony2.1, thanks to MonologBundle channels (Cookbook here) but if you are in Symfony2.0 and need to handle different log files this is the way to do so:
You&amp;#8217;ll have to define a new Logger service and a Handler service for that logger.</description></item><item><title>Resumen Q1 2012 - Muchos cambios</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2012-03-31-resumen-q1-2012-muchos-cambios/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 15:58:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2012-03-31-resumen-q1-2012-muchos-cambios/</guid><description>Hace poco más de 3 meses que hacía mi propia retrospectiva sobre el pasado año 2011. Y la verdad es que desde entonces han sucedido un montón de cosas sobre las cuales me apetece escribir un poco.
Desde aquel post, ha cambiado totalmente mi situación a nivel laboral y ya he conseguido cumplir alguno de los objetivos que me había propuesto para este 2012.
Para empezar, la comunidad Symfony Barcelona ya es una realidad.</description></item><item><title>Composer.json and Travis-ci for our Symfony2 Bundles</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2012-02-20-composer-json-travis-ci-for-symfony2-bundles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 22:37:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2012-02-20-composer-json-travis-ci-for-symfony2-bundles/</guid><description>Travis-CI and Packagist / composer.json are the new toys in the PHP community and specially amongst the Symfony2 developers crew.
I like Travis-CI because you can easily setup Continous Integration to some degree without having to setup a full working Jenkins (or whatever suite) environment and code can be tested with different PHP versions. This can be really useful to ensure that our code is ready for the incoming PHP5.</description></item><item><title>Resumen 2011 y Objetivos 2012</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2011-12-24-resumen-2011-y-objetivos-2012/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 16:46:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2011-12-24-resumen-2011-y-objetivos-2012/</guid><description>Vaya año más movido ha sido este 2011.
Resumen laboral Volviendo la vista atrás, en Enero estaba trabajando en Privalia, en el equipo de Front y aparentemente todo estaba bastante tranquilo. Junto a mis compañeros conseguimos elevar muchísimo la fiabilidad de las subidas de código, desarrollar buenas prácticas, hacer algo de Scrum y todo parecía ir en la buena dirección.
Pasamos por momentos algo duros, de mucha presión, debido a varios rediseños de la web completamente absurdos (el tiempo nos dio la razón y muchas cosas se echaron para atrás) y las interferencias de los managers pero salimos adelante con una nota bastante alta.</description></item><item><title>How to use Symfony2 validator component without forms (Entities and data arrays)</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2011-11-06-how-to-use-symfony2-validator-component-without-forms-entities-and-data-arrays/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 11:32:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2011-11-06-how-to-use-symfony2-validator-component-without-forms-entities-and-data-arrays/</guid><description>There seems to be a lot of confusion when using Symfony2 validation outside CRUD and Forms but the thing is that these component can be used in many ways to validate stuff all around the application.
I will show 2 examples of how we use validation component at Ulabox for 2 quite common issues in e-commerce:
Credit Card Validation using Entity Classes (without being linked to a table) and Annotations</description></item><item><title>Nacimiento del blog</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2010-11-03-nacimiento-del-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 23:40:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/posts/2010-11-03-nacimiento-del-blog/</guid><description>Tras asistir el pasado fin de semana a la PHP Barcelona Conference 2010 me he decidido a abrir esta página y intentar aportar alguna cosa más al mundillo de la programación web; en especial PHP, MySQL y JavaScript, que son las tecnologías con las que trabajo.
También intentaré poner alguna cosa de cómics, música y videojuegos que me parezca interesante.
Espero actualizar regularmente y que haya artículos de interés.
De momento tengo pensado ir subiendo parte de las transparencias que usaba en mi etapa de profesor de Programación en PHP y MySQL así como de preparación a la certificación Zend.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/about-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/about-me/</guid><description>I am a Technology Leader with a strong DevOps mindset specialising in high performance architectures handling millions of daily users and financial transactions in the cloud.
As a contractor with my company Rigor Alliance I am available for gigs helping your technical team boost their skills in automation, CI/CD, images creation, monitoring, observability, infrastructure as code, costs reduction and performance improvements.
I enjoy helping the tech community get together and level up co-organising the DevOps Barcelona Conference and the PHP Barcelona Conference</description></item><item><title>CVitae</title><link>https://www.ricardclau.com/curriculum-vitae-en/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ricardclau.com/curriculum-vitae-en/</guid><description>Contractor for hire As a contractor with my company Rigor Alliance I am available for gigs helping your technical team boost their skills in automation, CI/CD, images creation, monitoring, observability, infrastructure as code, costs reduction and performance improvements.
Standing out projects In the tech industry since 2002, I have been lucky enough to participate in a lot of excellent projects. Some of the most relevant ones are:
Rigor Alliance - Owner Holaluz - CTO Wonga - DevOps / Automation Team Lead Another Place Productions – Backend and Infrastructure Technical Lead Hailo – Technical Lead SocialPoint – Backend Technical Lead Ulabox - Software Architect Privalia - Software Architect Please check my Linkedin profile for further details on these and many other projects</description></item></channel></rss>